Guide to the Michael Ginsberg Books Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Michael Ginsberg Books records
1974-2007
WA MSS S-2691
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
100.02
(119 boxes)
The records of Michael Ginsberg Books includes financial records, catalogs, catalog cards, and appraisal records. Financial records consist of accounts, invoices, ledgers, receipts, checks, and statements. Catalogs include both inventory catalogs and lists of recent aquisitions from Michael Ginsberg Books as well as catalogs from other rare book dealers. Catalog cards record inventory items, the bulk of which are numbered sequentially. Appraisal records include notes, correspondence, and other papers related to appraisals conducted by Michael Ginsberg.
Michael Ginsberg Books
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Michael Ginsberg, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 118 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Scope and Contents
The records of Michael Ginsberg Books includes financial records, catalogs, catalog cards, and appraisal records. Financial records consist of accounts, invoices, ledgers, receipts, checks, and statements. Catalogs include both inventory catalogs and lists of recent aquisitions from Michael Ginsberg Books as well as catalogs from other rare book dealers. Catalog cards record inventory items, the bulk of which are numbered sequentially. Appraisal records include notes, correspondence, and other papers related to appraisals conducted by Michael Ginsberg.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Financial Records, 1974-2004. II. Catalogs, 1975-2007. III. Catalog Cards. IV. Appraisal Records, 1980s-1990s.
Booksellers and bookselling -- Massachusetts -- Sharon; Born digital; Electronic documents; Ginsberg, Michael; Michael Ginsberg Books
- Financial Records, 1974-2004; Series I; 74.8; (75 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged in rough chronological order.
  Scope and Contents
  Financial records consist of accounts, invoices, ledgers, receipts, checks, and statements. In most cases descriptions and date information were transcribed from boxes as received.
  - Accounts and receipts, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Accounts and receipts, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1975 September - 1976 August (Box 3)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1975 September - 1976 August (Box 4)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1975 September - 1976 August (Box 5)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1976 September - 1977 August (Box 6)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1976 September - 1977 August (Box 7)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1976 September - 1977 August (Box 8)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1976 September - 1977 August (Box 9)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Accounts and receipts, 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1980s (Box 13)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1980s (Box 14)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1981 September - 1982 August (Box 15)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1981 September - 1982 August (Box 16)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1981 September - 1982 August (Box 17)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1981 September - 1982 August (Box 18)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1982 September - 1983 September (Box 19)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1982 September - 1983 September (Box 20)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1984 September - 1985 August (Box 21)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1984 September - 1985 August (Box 22)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1985 September - 1986 August (Box 23)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1985 September - 1986 August (Box 24)
  - Invoices, 1986 September - 1987 August (Box 25)
  - Invoices, 1986 September - 1987 August (Box 26)
  - Invoices, 1986 September - 1987 August (Box 27)
  - Bookeeping #1, Checks, Statements, Journals, 1986-1994 (Box 28)
  - Bookeeping #1, Checks, Statements, Journals, 1986-1994 (Box 29)
  - Bookeeping #1, Checks, Statements, Journals, 1986-1994 (Box 30)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1987 September - 1988 December (Box 31)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1987 September - 1988 December (Box 32)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1987 September - 1988 December (Box 33)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1989 (Box 34)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1989 (Box 35)
  - Invoices, accounts, and ledgers, 1990 (Box 36)
  - Invoices, accounts, and ledgers, 1990 (Box 37)
  - Invoices, accounts, and ledgers, 1990 (Box 38)
  - Accounts, invoices, and ledgers, 1991 (Box 39)
  - Accounts, invoices, and ledgers, 1991 (Box 40)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1992-1993 (Box 41)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1992-1993 (Box 42)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1992-1993 (Box 43)
  - Invoices, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Invoices, 1993 (Box 45)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1994 (Box 47)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1995 (Box 48)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1995 (Box 49)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1996 (Box 50)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1996 (Box 51)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1997 (Box 52)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1997 (Box 53)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1997 (Box 54)
  - Accounts and receipts, 1998-1999 (Box 55)
  - Accounts and receipts, 1998-1999 (Box 56)
  - Payables, 1998-1999 (Box 57)
  - Payables, 1998-1999 (Box 58)
  - Payables, 1998-1999 (Box 59)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1999-2000 (Box 60)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1999-2000 (Box 61)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1999-2000 (Box 62)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1999-2000 (Box 63)
  - Accounts, 2001 (Box 64)
  - Accounts, 2001 (Box 65)
  - Files, 2001 (Box 66)
  - Files, 2001 (Box 67)
  - Accounts receivable, accounts payable, 2002 (Box 68)
  - Accounts receivable, accounts payable, 2002 (Box 69)
  - Accounts and invoices, 2003 (Box 70)
  - Accounts and invoices, 2003 (Box 71)
  - Accounts and invoices, 2003 (Box 72)
  - Accounts payable, accounts receivable, 2003-2004 (Box 73)
  - Accounts payable, accounts receivable, 2003-2004 (Box 74)
  - Accounts payable, accounts receivable, 2003-2004 (Box 75)
- Catalogs, 1975-2007; Series II; 7.92; (7 boxes)
  Catalogs are arranged in rough chronological order.
  Catalogs include both inventory catalogs and lists of recent aquisitions from Michael Ginsberg Books as well as catalogs from other rare book dealers, including William Reese Co.
  - Recent acquisition lists, 1975-1985 (Box 76)
  - Catalogs, 1985-1994 (Box 77)
  - Recent acquisition lists, 1989-1995 (Box 78)
  - Catalogs and recent acquisition lists, 1996-2002 (Box 79)
  - Catalogs, 2003-2007 (Box 80)
  - William Reese Co. catalogs, other catalogs (Box 81)
  - William Reese Co. catalogs, other catalogs (Box 82)
- Catalog Cards, Series III; 10.63; (26 boxes)
  Catalog cards are organized into two groups: numbered cards, which are arranged in numerical order, and unnmbered cards, which were filed in an alphabetical sequence.
  Catalog cards record item-level information about books, manuscripts, and other items in the inventory of Michael Ginsberg Books.
  - Numbered cards
    - 1-1199 (Box 83)
    - 1200-2500 (Box 84)
    - 2501-3800 (Box 85)
    - 3801-5000 (Box 86)
    - 5001-6300 (Box 87)
    - 7701-9000 (Box 88)
    - 9001-10,300 (Box 89)
    - 10,301-11,499 (Box 90)
    - 11,500-13,200 (Box 91)
    - 13,207-14,086 (Box 92)
    - 14,088-15,306 (Box 93)
    - 15,307-16,000 (Box 94)
    - 16,042-17,380 (Box 95)
    - 17,381-18,800 (Box 96)
    - 18,801-20,280 (Box 97)
    - 20,281-21,568 (Box 98)
    - 21,571-23,387 (Box 99)
    - 24,046-24,240 (Box 100)
    - 24,241-25,790 (Box 101)
    - 25,791-27,052 (Box 102)
    - 27,053-28,200 (Box 103)
    - 28,201-29,439 (Box 104)
    - 29,441-30,930 (Box 105)
    - 30,931-32,977 (Box 106)
  - Unnumbered cards
    - A-V (Box 107)
    - W-Z (Box 108)
- Appraisal Records, 1980s-1990s; Series IV; 5.21; (9 boxes)
  Arranaged in rough chronological order.
  Appraisal records include notes, correspondence, and other papers related to appraisals conducted by Michael Ginsberg. The bulk of the appraisal records relate to the William Russell Jazz Collection at the Historic New Orleans Collection.
  - Appraisals, 1980s-1990s (Box 109)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection appraisal, 1994 (Box 110)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection appraisal, 1994 (Box 111)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection finding aids, 1994 (Box 112)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection finding aids, 1994 (Box 113)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection finding aids, 1994 (Box 114)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection finding aids, 1994 (Box 115)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection finding aids, 1994 (Box 116)
  - William Russell Jazz Collection / Historic New Orleans Collection finding aids, 1994 (Box 117)
- Computer Media, 1.46; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Formatted 11/91 OWP 1993, 2011-wa-45139-0045; 1 (Box 118)
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - 1994 formatted OWP 1994, 2011-wa-45139-0046; 1 (Box 118)
  - FORMATTED 11/97 OWP 1995, 2011-wa-45139-0047; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP Month END 1/98 + 2/98, 2011-wa-45139-0001; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP MARch close 4/14/98, 2011-wa-45139-0002; 1 (Box 118)
  - DiSC #1 MICHAEL GINSBERG BOOKS, 2011-wa-45139-0003; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 6/10/98 MAY month END, 2011-wa-45139-0004; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP JUNE 98, 2011-wa-45139-0005; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 8/10/98, 2011-wa-45139-0006; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 8/98 - (9/10/98), 2011-wa-45139-0007; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP -- SEPT ME Oct '98, 2011-wa-45139-0008; 1 (Box 118)
  - Oct '98 OWP Nov. 9, '98, 2011-wa-45139-0009; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 11/98 12/9/98, 2011-wa-45139-0010; 1 (Box 118)
  - DISC #2 MICHAEL GINSBERG BOOKS., 2011-wa-45139-0011; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP APR 98 5/12/98, 2011-wa-45139-0012; 1 (Box 118)
  - 2/24/97 Jan. 97-end, 2011-wa-45139-0013; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - FEB close 3/10/97, 2011-wa-45139-0014; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 4/11/97 MARCH END, 2011-wa-45139-0015; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - 5/12/97, 2011-wa-45139-0016; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 6/10/96, 2011-wa-45139-0017; 1 (Box 118)
  - 6/11/97 OWP, 2011-wa-45139-0018; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP June July 16 '97, 2011-wa-45139-0019; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 8/12/97 July close, 2011-wa-45139-0020; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 9/12/97 AUG close, 2011-wa-45139-0021; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - Oct 14, 97, 2011-wa-45139-0022; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 11/17/97 Oct. close, 2011-wa-45139-0023; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP NOV. 97 (12/15/97), 2011-wa-45139-0024; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP YEAR END 1997 (3/28/98), 2011-wa-45139-0025; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - Jan '96 - close, 2011-wa-45139-0026; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 3/20/96, 2011-wa-45139-0027; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 4/10/96, 2011-wa-45139-0028; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - 5/10/96, 2011-wa-45139-0029; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - 6/10/96, 2011-wa-45139-0030; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - July 8, '96, 2011-wa-45139-0031; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - JULY 8/12/96 --, 2011-wa-45139-0032; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - AUGUST 9/7/96, 2011-wa-45139-0033; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP, SEPT, '96, 2011-wa-45139-0034; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP 11/11/96, 2011-wa-45139-0035; 1 (Box 118)
  - OWP - NOV '96, 2011-wa-45139-0036; 1 (Box 118)
  - 12/96 + yr end. -- FYE 1996 2/24/97, 2011-wa-45139-0037; 1 (Box 118)
  - C: OWP/OWP/MICHAELG 8/10/95 - OWP - BACK UP, 2011-wa-45139-0038; 1 (Box 118)
  - Doom #5 C: /OWP/OWP/MICHAEL G 9/10/95 - OWP BACK UP, 2011-wa-45139-0039; 1 (Box 118)
  - DOOM #6 OWP - BACK UP 10/6/95, 2011-wa-45139-0040; 1 (Box 118)
  - Doom #3 OWP BACKUP 11/13/95 - PART I, 2011-wa-45139-0041; 1 (Box 118)
  - 11/13/95 BACKUP II, 2011-wa-45139-0042; 1 (Box 118)
  - Doom #7 OWP - 12/8/95, 2011-wa-45139-0043; 1 (Box 118)
  - Doom 4 OWP: 12/31/95 COMPETE YEAR -- on 2/13/96, 2011-wa-45139-0044; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKEN BU, 2011-wa-45139-0048; 1 (Box 118)
  - QB2 11/28, 2011-wa-45139-0049; 1 (Box 118)
  - JAN 31 RECON - QUICKBOOK, 2011-wa-45139-0050; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS close 3/31/99 (4/14/99), 2011-wa-45139-0051; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS - April Close 5/10/99, 2011-wa-45139-0052; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Book - MAY Month End 6/10/99, 2011-wa-45139-0053; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quickbook - Month End - June 7/12/99, 2011-wa-45139-0054; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOK July 99, 2011-wa-45139-0055; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOK 8/99 (9/10/99), 2011-wa-45139-0056; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS 10/12/99, 2011-wa-45139-0057; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOK 11/9/99 October, 2011-wa-45139-0058; 1 (Box 118)
  - 9/1 WIN 98 START UP, 2011-wa-45139-0059; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Book 1 DATA - 7/26/00 BEFORE YE '99!, 2011-wa-45139-0060; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOK 2 7/26/00 BEFORE YE - '99, 2011-wa-45139-0061; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS 8/10 #2, 2011-wa-45139-0062; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS 8/10/00 #1, 2011-wa-45139-0063; 1 (Box 118)
  - Aug 2000 2 YE 99, 2011-wa-45139-0064; 1 (Box 118)
  - Aug 2000 1 YE 99, 2011-wa-45139-0065; 1 (Box 118)
  - AUG 2000 1, 2011-wa-45139-0066; 1 (Box 118)
  - AUG 2000 2, 2011-wa-45139-0067; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOK 98/ 10/11/00 SERT 00 clos 2, 2011-wa-45139-0068; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS - Sept 00 close 10/11/2000 1, 2011-wa-45139-0069; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Books 11/00 1, 2011-wa-45139-0070; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Books 11/00 2, 2011-wa-45139-0071; 1 (Box 118)
  - 1, 2011-wa-45139-0072 (Box 118)
  - 2, 2011-wa-45139-0073; 1 (Box 118)
  - 3, 2011-wa-45139-0074; 1 (Box 118)
  - MARCH 2002 FYE 01, 2011-wa-45139-0075; 1 (Box 118)
  - MARCH 2002 FYE 01 1, 2011-wa-45139-0076; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOK 2/8/02 1, 2011-wa-45139-0077; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOK 2/8/02 2, 2011-wa-45139-0078; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS FYE 2000 3/20/2001 1, 2011-wa-45139-0079; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS FYE 2000 3/20/01, 2011-wa-45139-0080; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS (MAY) 6/17/2001 #1, 2011-wa-45139-0081; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS #2 (MAY 6/7/2001, 2011-wa-45139-0082; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS BU 2 9/10/01, 2011-wa-45139-0083; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS BU 8/27/01 1 9/10/01, 2011-wa-45139-0084; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS 3 9/10/01, 2011-wa-45139-0085; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK 11/05/01 1, 2011-wa-45139-0086; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK 11/05/01 2, 2011-wa-45139-0087; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOK 11/05/01 3, 2011-wa-45139-0088; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Book FYE 2001 #1 1/9/02, 2011-wa-45139-0089; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS 12/08/01 #1, 2011-wa-45139-0090; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS 12/08/01 #2, 2011-wa-45139-0091; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOK FYE 2001 #2 1/9/02, 2011-wa-45139-0092; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOKS 4/02 1, 2011-wa-45139-0093; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Books 4/02, 2011-wa-45139-0094; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS 5/10/02, 2011-wa-45139-0095; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICKBOOKS 5/10/02 2, 2011-wa-45139-0096; 1 (Box 118)
  - QuickBooks 5/10/02 #3, 2011-wa-45139-0097; 1 (Box 118)
  - Quick Books 5/10/02 #4, 2011-wa-45139-0098; 1 (Box 118)
  - QUICK BOOK JUNE 02 1, 2011-wa-45139-0099; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICK BOOK JUNE 02 2, 2011-wa-45139-0100; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICK BOOK June 02 3, 2011-wa-45139-0101; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICKBOOKS 4/8/02 3, 2011-wa-45139-0102; 1 (Box 119)
  - Quickbooks 6/6/2002 1, 2011-wa-45139-0103; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICK BOOKS 6/6/02 #2, 2011-wa-45139-0104; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICKBOOK #3 6/6/02, 2011-wa-45139-0105; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICKBOOKS 11/02 2, 2011-wa-45139-0106; 1 (Box 119)
  - Quicks book 3 11/02, 2011-wa-45139-0107; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICKBOOKS 11/02 1, 2011-wa-45139-0108; 1 (Box 119)
  - Quick book 9/02 III, 2011-wa-45139-0109; 1 (Box 119)
  - QUICK BOOK 9/02 II, 2011-wa-45139-0110; 1 (Box 119)
  - Quickbook 9/02 I, 2011-wa-45139-0111; 1 (Box 119)